<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>0xsuk's blog</title><link>https://0xsuk.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on 0xsuk's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © {year} 0xsuk. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 16:26:18 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://0xsuk.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bugs and Questions</title><link>https://0xsuk.github.io/agitcms/bugs-and-questions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 16:23:37 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://0xsuk.github.io/agitcms/bugs-and-questions/</guid><description>If you want to report a bug or have a question, create a new issue. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to label it!</description></item><item><title>Integrated Terminal</title><link>https://0xsuk.github.io/agitcms/integrated-terminal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 16:18:56 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://0xsuk.github.io/agitcms/integrated-terminal/</guid><description>Press Ctrl + @ to open/hide.
Press ctrl+d to kill a process. If a process is killed, integrated terminal automatically closes.
Click + to add an instance.
If you navigate to Home while integrated terminal is open, all instances will be inaccesible, but still be running in the background.</description></item><item><title>Editor</title><link>https://0xsuk.github.io/agitcms/editor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 06:49:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xsuk.github.io/agitcms/editor/</guid><description>Media Agit CMS starts local http server on port 3001 to serve media for previewing purpose.
On Windows, You have to allow Agit CMS to starts http server when warning is shown.
![](${media_public_path}/example.png) will be parsed into http://localhost:3001/${media_public_path}/example.png in the right side previewer. (${media_public_path} is a media public path)
Image placed at the same folder as the markdown post file is in cannot be previewed at this version.
To quickly get image path you want to insert into the editor, Agit CMS has a file explorer shortcut button Media for it.</description></item><item><title>Configuration</title><link>https://0xsuk.github.io/agitcms/configuration/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 17:52:46 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://0xsuk.github.io/agitcms/configuration/</guid><description>Agit CMS configration is really simple.
There&amp;rsquo;s two configurations.
Global configuration: applies globally. Site configuration: applies only to specific site. Let&amp;rsquo;s start with Global configuration
Global configuration Navigate to Home (start page), and click on Settings in GLOBAL section of the sidebar.
Open Integrated Terminal with Ctrl+@ Disable this to prevent Agit CMS from opening an integrated terminal when ctrl+@ is captured.
Zoom Change zoom rate.
Site configuration Go to one of site you added, and click on Settings in SITE section of the sidebar.</description></item><item><title>Quick Start</title><link>https://0xsuk.github.io/agitcms/quick-start/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 08:01:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xsuk.github.io/agitcms/quick-start/</guid><description>Installation Install latest binary from here
When downloading a binary, some warning will be displayed because Agit CMS is yet to be trusted by Windows/Mac. To suppress warning and continue, please reference below. Mac: Find agitcms in Finder. Click on the app pressing ctrl key. Select &amp;#34;Open&amp;#34;. (Open a Mac app from an unidentified developer - Apple Support) Windows: If &amp;#34;Windows protected your PC&amp;#34;, click on &amp;#34;More info&amp;#34;, and select &amp;#34;Run anyway&amp;#34;.</description></item><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://0xsuk.github.io/agitcms/overview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 12:39:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xsuk.github.io/agitcms/overview/</guid><description>Agit CMS is a multi-platform desktop application built on top of Electron, which works as a frontend interface for any static site generator, like Hugo and Jekyll.
You need to have a ready-to-run static sites on your local computer, as Agit CMS works as a frontend interface for it.
Features Vertical split style markdown editor. type-aware frontmatter interface. Agit CMS provides a frontmatter interface which respects the type of each frontmatter property.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://0xsuk.github.io/posts/2022-07-19-how-to-install-ch340-on-ubuntu-22.04/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 16:26:18 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://0xsuk.github.io/posts/2022-07-19-how-to-install-ch340-on-ubuntu-22.04/</guid><description>Most linux has built in driver for ch340, except for Ubuntu 22.04.
There&amp;rsquo;s a couple of things to do if you want to upload code to arduino clone from Ubuntu 22.04.
Install Driver Go to https://github.com/juliagoda/CH341SER, and follow the instruction. Basically all you need to do is to clone the repo and run make and make load. You might want to sudo them if you get permission denied.
/dev/ttyUSB0 In order to make /dev/ttyUSB0 accesible, you have to sudo apt autoremove brltty.</description></item><item><title>How to use Agit CMS</title><link>https://0xsuk.github.io/agitcms-v0.0.2-alpha/how-to-use-agitcms/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 12:50:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xsuk.github.io/agitcms-v0.0.2-alpha/how-to-use-agitcms/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a documentation of how to use Agit CMS.
The project link: https://github.com/0xsuk/agitcms
Only thing you need is a static site, powered by whatever &amp;ldquo;markdown based&amp;rdquo; static site generators like Hugo, Jekyll, Next.js, Gatsby.js and so on.
&amp;ldquo;markdown based&amp;rdquo; means you write contents in markdown in your local PC.
Agit CMS is NOT a git based CMS, or API based CMS. It&amp;rsquo;s a desktop app for writing markdown posts. So you need ready-to-run static sites on your local PC.</description></item><item><title>Build your own markdown editor with React.js and Codemirror 6</title><link>https://0xsuk.github.io/posts/2022-03-25-build-your-own-markdown-editor-with-react.js-and-codemirror-6/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 02:41:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xsuk.github.io/posts/2022-03-25-build-your-own-markdown-editor-with-react.js-and-codemirror-6/</guid><description>Hi suk here. This post explains how to create markdown editor/previewer with React.js / Codemirror 6. I&amp;rsquo;m writing this down because I had to learn how to build markdown editor for my project (a desktop based headless CMS for markdown blogs). Hope this post helps someone like me.
Goal of this project We are going to create a simple markdown editor that works in your browser. If I write strings in markdown format in codemirror editor, React.</description></item><item><title>Creating a Blog with Hugo</title><link>https://0xsuk.github.io/posts/2022-02-11-creating-a-blog-with-hugo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 04:22:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xsuk.github.io/posts/2022-02-11-creating-a-blog-with-hugo/</guid><description>Hugo - Static Site Generator Hugo is a popular opensource static site generator that runs on your computer.
We are going to cover how to install hugo on your computer and run it to build a fast static website or a blog.
What is a static site? A static site prebuilds HTML/CSS/JavaScript code that will work as webpages, and serve them when users visit a website. In contrast, traditional dynamic website renders a webpage every time users visit a website.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://0xsuk.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xsuk.github.io/about/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a 17 years old self-taught programmer from Japan who loves technologies.
Learning
Web Development (React / Node.js / Golang) Machine Learning / Statistics Cyber Security / CTFs (HackTheBox/TryHackMe) Robotics I&amp;rsquo;m building a desktop based headless CMS for markdown blogs.
Links:
Twitter! HackTheBox TryHackMe</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://0xsuk.github.io/_contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xsuk.github.io/_contact/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Offline</title><link>https://0xsuk.github.io/offline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xsuk.github.io/offline/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>